<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Sina&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://sinairv.github.io/categories/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Sina&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 14:51:08 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sinairv.github.io/categories/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to reduce the pain of working with TFS using Git TFS</title>
      <link>https://sinairv.github.io/2016/11/24/how-to-reduce-the-pain-of-working-with-tfs-using-git-tfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 14:51:08 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinairv.github.io/2016/11/24/how-to-reduce-the-pain-of-working-with-tfs-using-git-tfs/</guid>
      <description>Git TFS is a program that extends git commands to talk to a TFS remote repository (instead of a git repository). It creates a real git repository and replays the TFS history on top of it. It can be treated as a real git repository except for when it comes to cloning and syncing. In spite of that it still makes a programmer&amp;rsquo;s life much easier.
The best starting point is the project&amp;rsquo;s ReadMe file on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Git with GitHub on Windows</title>
      <link>https://sinairv.github.io/2012/05/05/using-git-with-github-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 16:25:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinairv.github.io/2012/05/05/using-git-with-github-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Git and don&amp;rsquo;t know how to install Git on Windows, read my earlier post: How to Setup Git for Windows
In an earlier post, I described the preliminary steps required to work with git on CodePlex. However using git withGitHub requires more initial steps.
Generating SSH Keys. Before proceeding to Git operations we need to create SSH public and private keys, and register the public key on the GitHub site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Git with CodePlex on Windows</title>
      <link>https://sinairv.github.io/2012/05/02/using-git-with-codeplex-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 10:50:41 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinairv.github.io/2012/05/02/using-git-with-codeplex-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Git and don&amp;rsquo;t know how to install Git on Windows, read my earlier post: How to Setup Git for Windows
On 21 March 2012, the CodePlex team announced their support for Git.
Creating a project with Git as source control is very easy in CodePlex and is done with a few clicks at no time. Suppose the project name is CodePlexGitTest. In order to make any changes to the project structure you need to clone the project first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup Git for Windows</title>
      <link>https://sinairv.github.io/2012/05/01/how-to-setup-git-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 23:27:40 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sinairv.github.io/2012/05/01/how-to-setup-git-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>These are some easy steps required to setup Git for Windows:
 Download msysGit from: http://code.google.com/p/msysgit
I prefer to use the portable version. At the time of this writing there&amp;rsquo;s no difference between 32 bit and 64 bit versions and the filename for the portable version is: PortableGit-1.7.10-preview20120409.7z. Currently it seems that the development of the project has been moved to GitHub, but the releases are still located in Google Code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>