<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Qt | Sina Iravanian]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sinairv.com/blog/categories/qt/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sinairv.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-26T20:58:44+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sinairv.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sina Iravanian]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[sina.iravanian@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Built My First Qt Application in Visual Studio 2010]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sinairv.com/blog/2011/07/04/how-i-built-my-first-qt-application-in-visual-studio-2010/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-04T23:10:54+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sinairv.com/blog/2011/07/04/how-i-built-my-first-qt-application-in-visual-studio-2010</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I downloaded the Qt SDK (offline installer version which was 1.7 GB) from:
<a href="http://qt.nokia.com/downloads">http://qt.nokia.com/downloads</a></p>

<p>At the time of this writing, the Qt libraries version was 4.7.3.</p>

<p>Then I downloaded the VS-Addin, using the link at the bottom of the downloads page, titled &ldquo;Qt Visual Studio Add-in&rdquo;.</p>

<p>After installing both SDK, and the VS-Addin on my system, I started Visual Studio 2010. I tried to create a sample project by selecting: File > New > Project&hellip; > Qt4 Projects > Qt Application, and specified proper values for Name and Location. After going through the Qt wizard to the end, I encountered the following error message:</p>

<pre><code>unable to find Qt Build!
To solve this problem specify Qt Build!
</code></pre>

<p>By going to the Qt setup directory, one sees that there are Qt SDKs available for different target platforms. For example I installed Qt in &ldquo;D:\QtSDK\&rdquo; and in that directory I see some folders which correspond to different target platforms such as Desktop, Madde, Symbian, and others. An appropriate platform directory should contain a bin folder inside. This is true about Madde, and Symbian, but the Desktop folder is a root for subdirectories related to different Qt versions and C++ compilers. Since I wanted to develop Qt applications with Microsoft Visual C++ for the Windows Desktop platform I went to the following directory which contains the required bin folder:
D:\QtSDK\Desktop\Qt\4.7.3\msvc2008</p>

<p>For the next step, I had to introduce this directory for the Qt VS-addin. From the main menu, I selected Qt > Qt Options > Qt Versions. I pressed the Add button, and entered &ldquo;Win 4.7.3&rdquo; in the  &ldquo;Version name&rdquo; field, and entered the above path in the &ldquo;Path&rdquo; field, and pressed OK. The path that I specified was added to the gird. Then I made sure that in the Default Qt/Win version, the version that I have just specified (i.e., Win 4.7.3) is selected. I pressed OK, and tried once more with the Qt New Project wizard. This time everything went OK, and I succeeded to create and build my first Qt Application in the VS 2010 environment.</p>

<p>Note: In fact the current Qt binaries are targeted for Visual Studio 2008. I was able to use the binaries (i.e., libs and dlls) because I had also Visual Studio 2008 and the corresponding C++ compiler installed on my machine. Otherwise, I presume that I would need to recompile the sources with the VS-2010 C++ compiler.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
