<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Koan | Sina Iravanian]]></title>
  <link href="http://sinairv.github.io/blog/categories/koan/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sinairv.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-24T16:15:28+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://sinairv.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sina Iravanian]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[sina.iravanian@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Koans: One of the Best Ways to Learn a New Language or Framework]]></title>
    <link href="http://sinairv.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/programming-koans-one-of-the-best-ways-to-learn-a-new-language-or-framework/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T16:46:35+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://sinairv.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/programming-koans-one-of-the-best-ways-to-learn-a-new-language-or-framework</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Based on Wikipedia, originally a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K%C5%8Dan">Koan in Zen-practice</a> is a paradoxical question that provokes doubt and tests a student’s progress. On the other hand, programming Koans are a set of failing unit-tests, for which the learner is required to fix the code or fill the required fields with proper values in order to make each test pass. Probably one of the earliest and most popular Koans were <a href="http://rubykoans.com/">Ruby Koans</a>. Now there are several Koans implemented for different languages and frameworks. Search the word “Koan” in <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a> or <a href="https://bitbucket.org/">BitBucket</a> and you will find the gems.</p>

<p>My first experience of Koans was <a href="https://github.com/rally25rs/MoqKoans">MoqKoans</a>, a great set of Koans for learning <a href="http://code.google.com/p/moq/">Moq</a>, a mocking library for the .NET framework. That was really a wonderful learning experience. These days I’m trying to strengthen my web programming skills, and as one of the early steps I decided to remaster JavaScript. I found two JavaScript Koans on GitHub; both of them are great. However, I suggest that one should start with the <a href="https://github.com/liammclennan/JavaScript-Koans">JavaScript Koans by Liam McLennan</a>, which is easier to begin with. after finishing this step, I highly recommend proceeding with the<a href="https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/javascript-koans">JavaScript Koans by David Laing</a>. This one is a smaller set of Koans, but gets more advanced, and contains an introduction to <a href="http://underscorejs.org/">Underscore.js</a> as well.</p>

<p>Experience the joy of learning with Koans, and having all the reds going green in the end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
